A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1999-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1999-2000
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.021
This collection consists of ca. 25,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library in 2002 August.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by John Thomas Casteeen, the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
The papers consist of: general files, 1999-2000; seldom used permanent files, 1990-1998); and, committee files, 1999-2000.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1999-2000 Boxes 1-55
SERIES II: Seldom Used Permanent Files, 1990-1998 Boxes 56-65
SERIES III Committee Files, 1999-2000 Box 66
SERIES IV: Restricted Files Boxes 67-70
Contents List
- SERIES I: General Files
  - "A-AL" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - "AM" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - "AN-AZ" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Admissions (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Admissions-Law (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Admissions-Medical (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Woodson Institute (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association-General and Board of Managers (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities-AASCU (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - ACE Applications 1996 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education (ACE) The Presidency (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Architecture-General 1999-2000 (Box 3)
  - Art-General 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Arts, Planning, and Development 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Bayly Museum 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Assessment, Planning, and Studies (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Associated Chief Admissions Officers of Public Universities (ACAOPU) (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Associated Western Universities 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Association of Academic Health Centers 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (1-3 of 7) 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities (4-7 of 7) 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities (1-2 of 5) 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities (3-5 of 5) 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 7)
  - Association of Governing Boards-General 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Association of Governing Boards-Advisory Council of Presidents 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges-General 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Athletics-General (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Athletics-ACC (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Athletics-CFA (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 8)
  - Athletics-NCAA (1-4 of 8) 1999-2000 (Box 8)
  - Athletics-NCAA (4-8 of 8) 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - "BA-BM" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - "BN-BR" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - "BS-BZ" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Biology-General 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Birdwood-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Business and Finance-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Business and Finance-General Updates (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - "CA-CG" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 7) 1999-2000 (Box 12)
  - "CA-CG" Miscellaneous (4-7 of 7) 1999-2000 (Box 13)
  - "CH-CN" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2001 (Box 14)
  - "CO-CZ" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 14)
  - "CO-CZ" Miscellaneous (3-4 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Career Planning and Placement-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Casteen, John T., III-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Cavalier Daily-General 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Center for Innovative Technology-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Charlottesville, City of-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Charlottesville, City of-Planning and Coordination Council 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Chemistry-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Classics, Department of-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - College of Arts and Sciences-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - College Board-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Commerce-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Community Colleges-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Complaint/Request Forms-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Comptroller (State) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Condolences "A-Z" (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Congress-General 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Connie Lee-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Continuing Education-General (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Council of Presidents-General 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Council of Southern Universities-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - "DA-DE" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - "DF-DZ" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 17)
  - Development-General 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 18)
  - Development-General 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 18)
  - Drama, Department of-General 1999-2000 (Box 18)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 18)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Economics-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Education-General 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Educational Testing Service-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Endowment Fund 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Engineering and Applied Science (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 19)
  - Engineering and Building (State)-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - English, Department of-General (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Enrollment-Enrollment Statistics 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Environmental Sciences-General 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Equal Opportunity Office-General (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - "FA-FH" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - "FI-FZ" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Facilities Management-General 1999-2000 (Box 20)
  - Faculty-General 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences-General 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund-National Advisory Committee 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Financial Aid to Students-General 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - Food Services-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - French Language and Literature-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - "GA-GN" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - "GO-GZ" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - General Assembly-General (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 21)
  - General Assembly-General (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - General Assembly-Legislative Summaries 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - General Assembly-House Appropriations (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - General Assembly-Senate Finance 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - General Services-General 1999-2000 (Box 22)
  - German, Department of-General (empty) 1999-2001 (Box 22)
  - Gifts and Grants-"A-C" (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants-"D-F" (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 23)
  - Gifts and Grants-"G-K" (4 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 24)
  - Gifts and Grants-"L-P" (1-2 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 24)
  - Gifts and grants-"L-P" 3-4 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 25)
  - Gifts and Grants-"Q-S" (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 25)
  - Gifts and Grants-"T-Z" (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 26)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1999-2000 (Box 26)
  - Governmental and Community Relations 1999-2000 (Box 26)
  - Governor's Office-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 26)
  - Governor's Office-Administration (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Commerce and Trade 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Education (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Finance (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Health and Human Resources (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Technology 1998-1999 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Public Safety and Transportation 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Governor's Office-Washington Liaison Office (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - "HA-HH" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 27)
  - "HI-HZ" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - History, Department of 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - Honor System-General 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - Housing-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - Human Resources, Department of-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - Human Resources, Department of-Qual Choice (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 28)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 29)
  - Information Technology (State) 2000 (Box 29)
  - Information, Technology, and Communications 1999-2000 (Box 29)
  - International Students-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 29)
  - International Studies-General 1999-2000 (Box 29)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 30)
  - Invitations to Social Events 1999-2000 (Box 30)
  - "J" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 30)
  - Jefferson, Thomas Memorial Foundation-General 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - Jefferson Scholars 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Design Committee-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - Joint Legislative Audit Review Commission (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 31)
  - Law School-General (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - Lawn Policy Use-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - Lawn Society 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - Library-General 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - "MA-ME" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - "MF-MZ" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - "MC" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 32)
  - Major Events, Office of-General 1999-2000 (Box 33)
  - Management and Budget-General 1999-2000 (Box 33)
  - Marine Science-General 1999-2000 (Box 33)
  - Mariner's Museum 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 33)
  - Mariner's Museum (3 folders) 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 33)
  - Mathematics, department of-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 33)
  - Medical Center-General (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Medical Center-Personnel 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Medical Center-Health Sciences Council (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Medical Center-Hospital 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Medical Center-Medical School 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Medical Center-Nursing 1999-2000 (Box 34)
  - Miller Center (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 35)
  - Minority Affairs-General 1999-2000 (Box 35)
  - Music, Department of-General 1999-2000 (Box 35)
  - "N-NA" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - "NB-NZ" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land Grant Colleges-General 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - National Science Foundation 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - NASULGC-Board on Oceans and Atmosphere 1999-2001 (Box 37)
  - NASULGC-Committee on International Exchange (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 37)
  - NASULGC-Green Circulars (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 37)
  - National Institute of Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism-NIAA 1999-2000 (Box 37)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation CHEA-General (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 37)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation CHEA-General (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 38)
  - New England Loan Marketing Foundation/Sallie Mae-General (1-2 of 6) 1999-2000 (Box 38)
  - New England Loan Marketing Foundation/Sallie Mae-General (3-6 of 6) 1999-2000 (Box 39)
  - Newcomb Hall-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 39)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 40)
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities-General 1999-2000 (Box 40)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa-General 1999-2000 (Box 40)
  - "PA-PH" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 40)
  - "PI-PZ" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - General Transportation-General (University) 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Parking and Transportation-General State (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Personnel and Training (State)-General 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Philosophy, Department of-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Physics, Department of-General 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Physics-NEAL, SURA (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Planning-General 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Virginia 2020-General (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Planning and Budget-Capital Outlay 1999-2000 (Box 41)
  - Planning and Budget-U.Va. General 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - President's Cabinet (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - Promotions and Tenure (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - Provost-General 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - Psychology, Department of-General 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - "RA-RH" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - "RI-RZ" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 42)
  - Recommendations-"A-Z" (Restricted) 1999-2000 (Box 43)
  - Registrar-General 1999-2000 (Box 43)
  - Request for Nominations-"A-Z" (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 43)
  - ROTC-General 1999-2000 (Box 43)
  - ROTC-Air Force 1999-2000 (Box 43)
  - ROTC-Army (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 44)
  - ROTC-Air Force (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 44)
  - "SA-SH" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 44)
  - "SI-SN" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 44)
  - "SO" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 44)
  - "SP-SZ" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Salaries-General 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Senate (University Faculty) 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Slavic Languages and Literatures-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Sociology 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools-General (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - Southern Regional Educational Board--General 1999 (Box 45)
  - Sponsored Programs, Office of-General 1999-2000 (Box 45)
  - State Council of Higher Education (3 folders) 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 46)
  - State Council of Higher Education (2 folders) 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 46)
  - State Department of Education-General 1999-2000 (Box 46)
  - Student Affairs-General 1999-2000 Jan-Jun (Box 46)
  - Student Affairs-General 1999-2000 Jul-Dec (Box 47)
  - Student Affairs-Dean of Students Office-General 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Student Affairs-Fraternities/Sororities (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Student Council-General 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Student Council-Minutes 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - Summer Session-General 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - "TA-TE" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 47)
  - "TF-TZ" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 48)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 48)
  - University Research Association-General 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - United Way-General 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - University Guides-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - University Journal-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Co. (1-2 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 49)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Co. (3-4 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 50)
  - University of Virginia at the Wise 1999-2000 (Box 50)
  - Clinch Valley College-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 50)
  - University Police-General 1999-2000 (Box 50)
  - University Press of Virginia-General 1999-2000 (Box 51)
  - University Relations/News Office-General 1999-2000 (Box 51)
  - University Union-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 51)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 51)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 52)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council-General (1-2 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 52)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council-General (3-4 of 4) 1999-2000 (Box 53)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film 1999-2000 (Box 53)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1999-2000 (Box 53)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 54)
  - "W" Miscellaneous (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 55)
  - Wachovia Corporation-General (2 folders) 1999-2000 (Box 55)
  - Weldon Center for Public Service-General (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 55)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1999-2000 (Box 55)
- SERIES II: Seldom Used Permanent Files
  - Athletics-Director Search (5 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 56)
  - Athletics-Peach Bowl (2 folders) 1998 (Box 57)
  - Athletics-Micron PC.Com Bowl 1999 (Box 57)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation (1-3 of 6) 1998 (Box 57)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation (4-6 of 6) 1998 (Box 58)
  - Darden Campaign 1990 (Box 59)
  - Development-Arts and Sciences Long Range Develop. Plan 1986-1995 (Box 59)
  - Development Campaign Case Statement II (2 folders) 1994-1996 (Box 59)
  - Development-Capital Campaign/Computers 1992 (Box 60)
  - Development-Capital Campaign/Health Sciences Center 1994 (Box 60)
  - Development-Internal Development Group 1985-1986 (Box 60)
  - Development-Development Council (4 folders) 1992 (Box 60)
  - Governor's Commission on Government Reform-"Blue Ribbon Strike Force" (5 folders) 1994 (Box 61)
  - Governor's Office/Workforce Transition Act (3 folders) 1995-1997 (Box 62)
  - Governor-Executive Agreement (2 folders) 1982-1986 (Box 62)
  - Governor's Office/Commission on the Future of Higher Education (3 folders) 1995 (Box 62)
  - Medical Center-Institute for Substance Abuse Studies (1-3 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 63)
  - Medical Center-Institute for Substance Abuse Studies (4-5 of 5) 1999-2000 (Box 64)
  - Planning and Budget 1999-2000 (Box 64)
  - Planning and Budget-Capital Outlay 1988-1998 (Box 64)
  - Planning and Budget-University 1988-1994 (Box 64)
  - Visitors-General (5 folders) 1999 (Box 65)
- SERIES III: Committee Files
  - University Committees-Benefits Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Public Occasions Subcommittee/Commencement 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Commencement and Convocations (empty) 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-EOP/Affirmative Action Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Financial Aid Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Information Tech Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Libraries Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Master Planning Council 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Radiation Safety Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Undergraduate Admissions Committee 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-University Press of Virginia Board of Directors 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Virginia Quarterly Review Board 1999-2000 (Box 66)
  - University Committees-Committee on the Virginia Status of University Students 1999-2000 (Box 66)
- SERIES IV: Restricted Files (Box 67-70)